<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[andrelop's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-18T07:22:59-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrelop.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[André Luís Lopes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up a Work Environment Under Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/17/setting-up-a-work-environment-under-windows/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-17T23:48:58-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/17/setting-up-a-work-environment-under-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m such an old person. So much that I was becoming sick of having
to tinker with the operating system in order to do basic routine tasks.</p>

<p>What I needed was somehting which I could use for my work and home
computing needs, without having to deal too much with the hassle of
having to fix Bluetooth support, Flash video, dual-monitor setup,
codec configuration and all those crap one needs to deal with
when using Linux as a desktop operating system.</p>

<p>For a while, I used OSX. I was being the happy owner of a gorgeous
MacBook white (since 2007 until sometime last year). It was perfect for
my needs because it had everything I needed for work environment (a
working Unix-like operating system) plus a nicely and beautiful,
crap-aware end end user environment.</p>

<p>However, time went by fast and many software and operating system
updates later I realised hardware was becoming a bottleneck. Everything
became slow to use and painfulness turned out to be the standard.</p>

<p>As I was quite satisfied by the Apple experience I tried to go
shopping for a new machine from the same company. Sadly, money
doesn&rsquo;t grow on trees and Apple hardware here in Brazil is insanely
expensive.</p>

<p>My option would be to buy a PC-style laptop from one of the various
vendors and use Linux again. Guess what ? I did not wanted to suffer
from crap-unawareness again so this wasn&rsquo;s a real option.</p>

<p>What other option is out there ? Yes, Windows. I knew Windows had
all the support for all the crapiliciousness out there, plus it
could run games, something which would sometimes made me a little bit
happier than the usual.</p>

<p>Yes, OSX can run some games, but the hardware isn&rsquo;t the most indicated
for this kind of task. Besides, for something a little bit closer
to a minimally decent gaming experience under OSX one would need to
sell body parts to pay for it (Apple hardware upgrades are really
expensive and even paying for it with both of your eyes one would
still not get a good gaming platform in the end).</p>

<p>I went shopping for a replacement laptop and found one from Dell which
would give me a really good platform for both work and home/fun.
I&rsquo;ve been using it since sometime already, but I never was 100% happy
when it came to the work part of the equation.</p>

<p>For home usage it was perfect as I could play games and use all the
crap one could imagine. For work, I kept using Virtualbox VMs. It
worked, but then it wasn&rsquo;t great to keep those Windows Virtualbox
windows open (Virtualbox admin Windows AND the VM-in-use-window)
only to use a terminal emulator.</p>

<p>PuTTy, the terminal emulator for Windows, wasn&rsquo;t that great for
someone used to native Linux terminal emulators. Sometime ago a
friend of mine gave a tip about MobaXTerm, which is a on-steroids
terminal emulator with a Cygwin environment built-in (plus a lot
of other goodies).</p>

<p>It was centuries ahead of PuTTy when it comes to being productive
for sysadmin work (Linux servers) from a Windows box. Still, not
having a full Linux environment sometimes had its advantages.
MobaXterm offers a lot of plugins in order to improve the Unix
environment experience, but there&rsquo;s always things you need and
for which there&rsquo;s no plugin available.</p>

<p>What I did to solve my problem was to create a really minimal
Virtualbox VM (Debian-based, obviously), with no X and nothing
but the absolute mininum needed to do my work. This machine
is reachable via SSH from the Windows host only and MobaXterm
is configured to open a SSH connection to it using a previously
saved session.</p>

<p>Also, this minimal VM is started in headless mode so there&rsquo;s no
need for any window floating around without being useful. It
boots up automatically along Windows, without being noticed,
and sits there waiting for my SSH connection.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s being used for work and for any use of a proper Linux
environment whenever I feel the need for it. Actually, it&rsquo;s
working so well that I&rsquo;ve migrated my main blog post writing
platform to run under this VM (git and vim are the only tools
needed).</p>

<p>Works like a charm :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Bike Tubes]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/12/on-bike-tubes/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T11:11:11-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/12/on-bike-tubes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I got myself a bike. At first, I thought buying the
thing would be all I needed to motivate me to got out more often and enjoy
nature.</p>

<p>However, I couldn&rsquo;t be more wrong. It&rsquo;s been around three months since I
bought the bike but I went out biking only two times. It&rsquo;s a speed bike so
it&rsquo;s not easy to ride it anywhere.</p>

<p>I mean, an usual bike can be used anywhere; streets, trails, roads, etc, but
a speed one isn&rsquo;t much fun to ride in places others than proper bike lanes
and/or nicely maintained roads (ie, the ones not suffering from the hole
disease).</p>

<p>Even when using <a href="http://www.cptm.sp.gov.br/e_noticias/Campanhas/ciclovia_riopinheiros.asp">&ldquo;ciclofaixas&rdquo;</a>
you&rsquo;re going to get some flat tires. Actually, the two times I went out riding
I came back home with flat tires. That&rsquo;s a little bit disappointing.</p>

<p>The first time I received this &ldquo;gift&rdquo; I looked up online for tips on how
to avoid it and then got myself some <a href="http://www.biketown.com.br/produto/pecas-fita-aro-anti-furo/fita-anti-furo-para-bicicletas-speed-road-tectire-aro-700c-22mm-x-2-2mts-par-tectire-2377.mstp">prevention for flat tires</a>.
Alas, I found out that it did not prevented another flat tire to
happen.</p>

<p>I then asked a friend which seems to know more than myself about bikes
what I could do to prevent it from happening again (or at least minimize
the possibilities) and got an advice about buying <a href="http://www.biketown.com.br/produto/pecas-camara-ar/camara-de-ar-vittoria-speed-road-ultralite-700-x-19-23c-valvula-presta-51mm-vittoria-1801.mstp">better tubes</a>.</p>

<p>I know that there&rsquo;re much better tubes but I don&rsquo;t want to spend too
much money on it, since I&rsquo;m not going to go pro on this bike thing.
I just want to have a bike I can ride and not come home with flat tires
everytime I go out riding.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s see what happens next time I go out biking using these new tubes.
If there&rsquo;re better advices about this tube/flat tire thing, I&rsquo;m listening.
Comments are enabled :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/12/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T10:10:06-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/12/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello,</p>

<p>This is my very first blog post. Bear with me while I try my best not to
screw everything up. It&rsquo;s all completey new to me :</p>

<ul>
<li>First time using Octopress</li>
<li>First time using GitHub Pages</li>
<li>First time using a git-enabled blogging engine</li>
<li>First time starting a blog using english only (sort of, we&rsquo;ll see)</li>
<li>First time blogging not from my local laptop, but from a VPS shell instead</li>
</ul>


<p>This is all to remind you that there surelly will be mistakes. Most likely
lots of them. But it&rsquo;s OK, I&rsquo;ll try to minimize them with time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
