<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Environment | andrelop's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/blog/categories/environment/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-26T00:54:31-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrelop.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[André Luís Lopes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battle for Keeping the Windows Work Environment]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/26/battle-for-keeping-the-windows-work-environment/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-26T00:21:30-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrelop.github.io/blog/2014/04/26/battle-for-keeping-the-windows-work-environment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I&rsquo;m still fighting to improve my Windows environment. It seemed
to be good enough until a couple of days ago, but then I got a new
toy at work.</p>

<p>Some days ago I got a Mac Mini to use as my desktop at work and
became addicted to OSX again. It&rsquo;s not easy to escape from Apple
environment once you experience it.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not perfect, but I&rsquo;ve to admit that it&rsquo;s the closer to the
ideal environment I&rsquo;ve ever experienced. It has lots of little
details which aren&rsquo;t big things, but when you add alll of them
together they become something really enjoyable to work with.</p>

<p>The one thing which really is a must is the Apple keyboard.
Once you get used to it you won&rsquo;t want to go back to anything
else. So much that I had to give up and order one for using at
home. Never looked back to my other keyboards since then.</p>

<p>Next, the two most productive details for me are Spotlight and
fast virtual desktop switching (don&rsquo;t know exactly how it&rsquo;s called
is OSX). After I experienced they again on OSX at work I knew I had
to get it working at home as well.</p>

<p>I went out shopping for solutions which could deliver these features
for Windows and found FARR (Find and Run Robot) for acting as a
Spotlight-like solution and VirtualWin, offering the fast virtual
desktop switching solution.</p>

<p>Both of them are free applications which work really well together.
They allow me to have separated virtual desktops for research, work,
fun, learning, remote shell access, etc, as well as start applications
really fast without needing to use the mouse.</p>

<p>Also, I&rsquo;ve to point out that if you use glasses and need to keep the
brightness of your screen under control at night, flu.x is your friend
(it&rsquo;s multi-platform, ie, it works under Windows, Linux and OSX).</p>

<p>Prior to these adjustments, I was considering buying a Mac Mini for
home usage. Actually, it&rsquo;s not somehting completely out of question yet.
However, now I can have the most important features (for me at least)
in a environment I already have at home.</p>

<p>Buying a Mac Mini would be the best option, but not something I would
do right now as it&rsquo;s a little bit expensive for me, even if the Mini
is the cheaptes way to run OSX, and specially if you&rsquo;re a Brazilian.</p>

<p>The Mini would be an awesome product to have at home and everything
I could need to run under Windows or Linux could be done using a
virtual machine under the Mini.</p>

<p>Also, despite VirtualBox working fine under OSX, I suspect buying a
Paralles license would be worth it as the features it offers when it
comes to nicely integrate Windows and/or Linux applications inside
OSX&rsquo;s environment are very interesting.</p>

<p>Well, not today kid. Not today :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
